<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" 
            schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
            href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	        schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 

            href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	        schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
        ?>
<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <body>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 1:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Thank you to Professor Elisabeth Burr and the University of Leipzig for inviting me to participate in this exciting lecture series on data literacy and digital humanities. And thank you all for coming to this talk, in the midst of the ways in which the pandemic has changed our professional abilities and opportunities to engage in discussions about our scholarship, as well as being so close for many to the end of term and the holidays. To say that we are exhausted is an understatement. But still, we have moments like this when we can come together - even virtually (or perhaps in ways otherwise impossible </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="italic">because</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"> of the virtuality) to discuss, and think, and explore the questions that inform our scholarship and our teaching.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Before I continue I would like to acknowledge that I have a tendency to speak fast - especially when I am nervous - and I apologize in advance for that. I will share the script of this talk and the slides in the next day or so. I also encourage you to reach out to me to continue this discussion.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">I am intrigued by the theme of this series, and by the challenge Professor Burr posed of us as participants: not just how should we teach the digital humanities, but ‘how should we teach data literacy in the Humanities?’ And how do we do this in a moment when everything we know in our lives, not least of all including </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="italic">how</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"> we can teach, is even more complex than the ways in which we usually think of digital humanities pedagogy.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Today I would like to talk with you about different ways in which we can engage our students in the digital humanities by sharing with them and including them in our research. This approach to pedagogy, while not revolutionary, provides our students with a more practical understanding of the value of the kinds of analysis with which we engage:  shifting from the theoretical framework in which we often present concepts and methods in the classroom, offering more tangible, practical ways for them to gain proficiency with “code” to interpret data, and providing them with a sense of agency in scholarly spaces - something that undergraduates, at least, don’t often have the opportunity to engage in. Digital humanities pedagogy is a subject I spend an enormous amount of time thinking about. My friend Brian Croxall and I are co-editing a volume on pedagogy for the Debates in DH series, and in a recent discussion we both realized how very committed we are to the ways in which DH plays out pedagogically in and out of the classroom. So I am grateful for the timing of this talk, as it amplifies what is in my mind.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">I intend to shape today’s discussion in terms of how I, at my institution, include students in my research project, REED London Online, and how through this engagement introduce them to a broader understanding of how we as professional scholars continually teach ourselves and one another, how we develop new competencies in order to move our research into forever more complex and sophisticated realms. I firmly believe that to include my students in my work is valuable - sometimes absolutely transformative - for all of us. But as Professor Burr has stated, the ways in which we work, especially when we involve our students, has ethical, social, and political consequences. And that is where I would like to guide us today - hopefully to moments for discussion in which we can be more thoughtful and intentional about these new moments of engagement that move us all away from traditional classrooms.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 2:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">By means of providing context, I will take a moment to describe my institution, and then dive into what REED London is and how my students participate in its work with me. My home institution is Bucknell University, an undergraduate liberal arts university of a little more than 3,000 students in rural Pennsylvania. The university is structured into three colleges: Arts &amp; Sciences, Engineering, and Management, but unlike larger institutions there is a degree of porousness between the colleges such that students in my DH classrooms are as likely to be from Biology or Computer Science or Accounting as they are to be from English or Philosophy. Bucknell is also very proud of the emphasis it places on undergraduate research, and we are all encouraged to find ways to integrate students into our research as well as to support them in undertaking their own, whether it be an independent project, an honors thesis, or a capstone or culminating experience. We make time for students to undertake research during the summers as well as the academic year, and the university provides incentives for doing so: students receive academic credit </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">or</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"> stipends or hourly pay for this type of work, and it has become a kind of hallmark of Bucknell’s self-promotion. It won’t be a surprise that most of the research opportunities overseen by faculty here come in the sciences. Humanities faculty at Bucknell, as I expect at other institutions have traditionally found it difficult to include students in their research projects, which are often publication-focused and involve advanced levels of competency in languages, theory, or interpretation that is beyond what can be expected of an undergraduate and is likely to ‘take us off our game’ as we mentor them. DH has been heralded as a space where students can take part in even a portion of a humanities research project. I can’t expect my students to read medieval Latin, or even medieval English, for that matter. But I can involve them in data mining, text encoding, and spatial analysis that actually </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="italic">does</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"> help me in my work rather than distract me from it.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">At Bucknell we have a robust slate of introductory, intermediate, and advanced DH courses and have developed a DH minor, which draws students from across the arts &amp; sciences. The one course that all students who opt for the minor must take is “Humanities 100”, the introductory course that focuses on methods often rooted in scholarly inquiry - use cases, if you will - rather than more abstract hypotheticals.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">I’ll pause here to explain what I mean by this. Research-based learning is a term that Janelle Jenstad of the University of Victoria introduced me to years ago. In essence, research-based learning integrates inquiry and (in my case) undergraduate research as a means to change learning paradigms. It is an approach that works particularly well in the digital humanities classroom: something my colleague Katie Faull and I have spoken and written about in the past. This approach to teaching can be exciting for both instructors and students. It provides a chance for us to demystify the digital as well as the humanities in our work. It gives students an opportunity to act as ‘apprentices’, shifting from the theoretical and abstract to something tangible and practical as they learn these new (to them) methods and tools that we use in our analysis and presentation.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">The Humanities 100 course that Katie Faull and I developed is a research-based learning experience, wherein students use one corpus, often drawn from our own research agendas, and interrogate that corpus via straightforward text analysis using the Voyant tool suite, TEI text encoding, data visualization through platforms like Palladio, and spatial analysis through ArcGIS. It’s an ambitious syllabus, and students usually fall into one of two camps: those who fall in love with the text, and those who thrive in visualizing data. At the risk of sounding manipulative, which I assure you I’m not, the course serves in many cases as a ‘feeder’ for students to become involved in our DH research projects, and many have participated in a range of projects with faculty across the university. </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 3:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Since 2016 I’ve had six students work with me on REED London in various capacities. And so I should stop here and explain what REED London is. </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">The REED London project is a large-scale collaborative project that involves scholars from the Canadian Writing Research Collaboratory, the University of Toronto, and Newcastle University in the UK, among others. It emanates from the Records of Early English Drama - a massive research project now in its fourth decade - whose mission is to discover documentary evidence of performance, theatre, and music in England, Scotland and Wales from 1100 to 1642. The editorial staff of the Records of Early English Drama excerpts, edits, and compiles archival documentary materials, drawing upon legal proceedings, household financial accounts, ecclesiastical and municipal business reports, and correspondence, to better understand the conditions in which pre-modern performance was undertaken, as well as the impact and influence it had on British society. To date it has produced 27 printed collections as well as 3 electronic collections that focus mainly on the English provinces. Playtexts, musical scores, lyrics, and the like have usually not been featured. The project has been instrumental in situating English theatre and performance away from bardolatry, which might be the impetus for holding back on London for so long. It was only 2010 when three print collections focusing on aspects of performance in the City of London were published: Inns of Court, Ecclesiastical, and Civic to 1558. Tens of thousands of references ranging from a single line tracking payment for the torchbearer who lit the way for a group of masquers to long-form excerpted letters describing Christmas revels at Court.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">The goal of REED London is to pull the records that are London-centric into a comprehensive digital resource that incorporates not only the excerpted transcribed and encoded documents that recall the events, but also reveal more fully the people and places that are named in them.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 4:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">These London collections appeared at the same time that REED realized - along with many such endeavours - began looking for new ways to make this massive output available to scholars and students. The editorial board committed itself to make existing and future work openly available in whatever form that work should take; it also began to develop new ways to present selections from the research through digital resources and databases like Patrons &amp; Performances and Early Modern London Theatre.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">This actually revealed the true nature of REED: that the volumes collectively form a massive printed database - in many ways impossible for scholars to use effectively separated as it is on paper by year-range and across county borders. One is hard-pressed to read a REED volume front-to-back. The project would seem to be perfectly suited for a shift from a print to a digital database. And yet I would aver that the potential for REED in a digital environment transcends the idea of a queriable relational database, and that its real value in a scholarly sense - and in the larger untapped pedagogical sense - lies in restructuring and re-presenting the documentary material to capitalize on new forms of reading inherent in the digital frame - reading that is both close and distant, discrete and dialectic, and is surprisingly akin to ways in which one might consult a medieval manuscript, with text, images, and glosses woven together and not isolated as they can be in print.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">It is through this lens of performance and the business of performance that REED London engages in our forensic analysis. In this context the confluence of subject matter and evidence reveals much more than cultural expression. Through the contemporary witnesses and participants we aim to better understand how pre-modern London *worked*, and how Londoners understood their City and their relationship to it.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 5:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">In 2016 I took on the role of lead investigator for REED London, with the mandate to:</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Bring the three printed London collections online</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Integrate the existing digital resources with these collections</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Prepare a stable publication environment that would anticipate new editions and collections</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">The goal, then, was to publish all of these documentary materials as well as editorial apparatus, glosses, and associated bibliographic material; in the process, we had to literally and figuratively break the spines of the printed volumes, and transliterate from print conventions while determining what a REED London record actually *is*, and how these record objects can be re-integrated to offer more holistic contextual meaning.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 6:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Thanks to the generous support and encouragement of the Canadian Writing Research Collaboratory and funding from the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation and the National Historical Publications and Records Commission of the US National Archives, we began to think intentionally about what REED London might look like and how it might be used in a digital frame; we also concentrated on sustainability: how we could support this work as it moves forward with increasingly decentralized editor clusters in Canada, the U.S. and Britain. </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 7:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">We’ve been able to do this work because of our collaboration with CWRC, which has enabled us to ingest, analyze, and begin to publish the records and editorial materials *across* collections. </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 8:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">To date the REED London project team ingested 300 records into CWRC, tagged them semantically to uncover social relationships among performers and patrons and patterns related to the transactional nature of performance in late Elizabethan and early Jacobean London. We created an authority list of over 2,300 person and 270 place entities and are in the process of making them available to the semantic web; we began the development of an ontology of occupations, offices, and objects mentioned in the records. Because the scoped material worked with during the planning phase - REED: Inns of Court - already existed in print published form, much of the work involved deconstructing what amounted to a print database. The work as scoped for the planning grant phase and the materials we produced allowed us to think carefully about the components of published archival work (artifacts, scholarly annotations, glosses, bibliographical citations, head notes, etc.) and to find ways to link among and across them - sometimes purposefully and sometimes to encourage new moments of discovery and connection for new and expanded groups of scholars and students.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 9:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">The REED London project team spent the majority of that first year *un*publishing- if you will - the Inns of Court collection and pulling it piece by piece into an editorial production environment in CWRC and using CWRC-Writer. Inns of Court was selected as the first phase of this work because it constitutes a relatively straightforward set of documents, and because one of the editors of the printed collection, Alan Nelson, is still an active REED editor on other projects and might be able to help us in our transliteration. The choice of Inns of Court has also helped us to think about expanding our user base to include scholars who are pointedly *not* theatre historians. The Inns of Court records include a remarkable array of documents that are potentially more valuable to scholars interested in legal, economic, and political history, focusing as they do on references to parliamentarians who paid for and participated in politically-motivated events and networks that often crossed class- and generation-lines involving the nobility, professionals, guildsmen (and women), and students. The performance piece, one might think, provides one of many lenses for a scholar of pre-modern subjects; we think that these excerpted records can offer scholars who have not before consulted REED to use it to fill in the gaps in their own research.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 10:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">As often as not these people and places are better known to history in other contexts and so REED London presents the City as a kind of Jabermassian formulation, where publics and counterpublics thrived and cohered in multivalent ways around performance events. </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 11, SLIDE 12:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">To tease out the details of these events we rely on a dialogic reading of contemporary sources through richly encoded texts. For some details we look at letters, such as this one from John Chamberlain to Alice Carleton describing the Memorable masque performed at the Banqueting House at Whitehall Palace.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 13:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">We also look at the list of expenses by the gentlemen of Lincoln’s Inn, who paid for that performance (and went into debt in the process). Here we see payments for the services of musicians, haberdashers, saddlers, and for all manner of clothing and objects required for the masque to go on.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">In this way we consider not only who performed and who witnessed a performance event, but also who sold the fabric that would be used for costumes and sets, who built and struck the stages and scaffolds, who repaired the instruments, who loaned the money so that a place could be performed …. And in so doing we break away from old modes of understanding theatrical performance as involving actors and audience, and think instead of the City of London and the business relationships that created intersections among groups, guilds, and breaking across socio-economic strata. </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 14:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">In CWRC we’ve begun to pull the information we’ve gleaned into different tools, including the integrated Voyant Tools, the Dynamic Table of Contexts, and begun to experiment with how the relationships among entities might be conceptualized in tools like HuViz.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">So, we’ve tackled the publication part, creating a stable TEI structure that accommodates dozens of record types, along with the reintegrated editorial apparatus that had been disconnected in its print form. We have folded back together and put inline notes and glosses that had been consigned to footers and back matter and different volumes entirely. As well as translated versions of documents in Latin, Spanish, French, and Italian to reinforce the work of editors and glossarians and bibliographers.  We also began to think about how we might create connections across records, using Alan Nelson’s editorial interpretations as the thread.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">In consultation with medievalists and early modernists who draw on REED for their research, we’ve begun to think about how this environment offers us new ways to create readable editorial context for this work. I’ve always found it difficult to find what I’m looking for in REED - the organizing parameters of time and place in a print mode do not always provide the best organization for these disparate record sets related to one event, or performance troupe, or central figure. Historical research is always an exercise in discovery, but a frustration by some with REED was that you only ever found what you were looking for if you knew what you were looking for.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 15, 16:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Here we’ve begun to consider ways in which we can present clusters of records related in some way to one another. Our prototype has been to focus on the wedding masques of 1612-14 for Frances Howard and Robert Kerr, and Princess Elizabeth and Frederick the Count Palatine. Both of these weddings had significant political importance; the married couples being related to or close to King James and the members of the Inns of Court fell over themselves to demonstrate their fealty to the crown by bankrolling and performing in incredibly lavish entertainments. By providing this context and creating pointed access to related documents, we can begin to think about how the records might more easily be found and *read* by students who are studying drama - as well as scholars seeking out arcane references to Inigo Jones.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">This leads me to another form of readability and ultimately to ways in which we hope to make REED London discoverable to and interchangeable with other like-minded (and perhaps *not* like-minded) DH projects. We have used the extensive indexes of the three printed London collections and harvested from them a remarkable list of people and places, as well as complex taxonomies of organizations, occupations, and ‘things’ referred to in the records. These indexes have given us a huge step up to begin the process of connecting our named entities to those with value to other digital projects. In printed form, REED London was a walled garden – Queen Elizabeth is included in REED’s index only because she was a patron and an audience member; and so she is isolated by REED - or duplicated from other authoritative Queen Elizabeth(s) recognized across the semantic web. </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Working closely with the CWRC team has helped us to think not just that we share our people and taxonomies, but how we do that and what we can accomplish in terms of discoverability and readability through that act of connection.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDES 17 </hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">And we’re just now beginning to think about how we should consider London place identities - or complicating the identities of places not usually known as related to performance.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDES 18, 19, 20, 21</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Maureen: Geography/GIS/historical place. First phase of research on the gazetteer. Struggled during her senior year and so work slowed down. Now in grad school for info science.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Rachel: Classics/Italian. First sought out neoclassical influence on court masques, but then became curious about political narratives that played out spatially.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 22:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Charlotte: Classics/pre-law. Started out semantic tagging in CWRC-Writer and became fascinated with financial transactions. Now has undertaken a new mode of encoding that teases out these transactions, connecting to MEDEA/DEPCHA.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 23:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Guillermo: CS. Fell in love with TEI in Oxygen. I’ll be bringing him on board in spring to work with LINCS and Bucknell faculty in CS to understand machine-learning and linked open data.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 24:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">This year I’ve been fortunate in that the Mellon grant allowed me to hire Charlotte and Rachel over the summer (and over the coming break), and even when we weren’t certain whether and when we would be teaching in person this fall, the nature of the work I do with these students has enabled us to keep going - unlike other lab-oriented research projects we were able to be productive at a remove. In some ways I think we were able to do some thinking about how the project might evolve </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">because</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"> we were working remotely.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">But undertaking this form of pedagogy, in which the lines blur between assignment and task, between grade-based economy and financial compensation and professional recognition … there are complexities about the shift in our relationship with those students, the responsibilities we as investigators must maintain, and the ethics of incorporating students in our work that is not only gratifying but imbues in them (and us) a respect for the work and for the people who engage in it. Because at the end of the day, we cannot escape the hierarchies that are baked into the academy - and most certainly structure the ways in which we understand one another.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 25:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">So to the central question I would like to pose: what happens when we take our teaching out of the classroom and integrate our students into our research? What should we expect of them - and ourselves - that is different from our expectations of them - and ourselves - in a curricular context? What do they have the right to expect of us?  How do we manage to be both their teachers and their mentors? When we call them research assistants - especially as undergraduates - is it fair of us to expect a level of professional maturity that we might expect of graduate students or postdocs, let alone our peers? What happens when they exceed our expectations for their work? What happens if they don’t achieve what we task them with? What kind of responsibilities can we place on them, and what kind of responsibility does this require of us?</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">
         <hi rend="bold">SLIDE 26:</hi>
      </p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main">Thank you.</p>
      <p xmlns:cp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/package/2006/metadata/core-properties"
         xmlns:office="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/extended-properties"
         xmlns:pkg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/2006/xmlPackage"
         xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
         xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main"/>
   </body>
</text>
